A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 13949-17726 FA739F
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Reflection memo (Reports 017074), 2005 (Box 874, Reel R-9323)
  Reflection memo prepared by Borislav Petranov outlining the human rights work in Russia, with emphasis placed on legal rights and community building.
  Human rights -- Russia (Federation); Community development, Urban -- Russia (Federation); Human rights movements -- Russia (Federation)
- Reflection memo (Reports 017075), 2004 (Box 874, Reel R-9323)
  Reflection memo prepared by Ujjwal Pradhan evaluating the environmental issues addressed by the Jakarta office, with emphasis placed on watershed and forestry.
  Logging -- Environmental aspects -- Indonesia; Forests and forestry -- Economic aspects -- Indonesia; Environmental responsibility -- Indonesia; Forest restoration -- Indonesia; Watersheds -- Indonesia; Conservation of natural resources -- Indonesia
- Reflection memo (Reports 017076), 2005 (Box 874, Reel R-9323)
  Reflection memo prepared by Ujjwal Pradhan addressing the field of environmental sustainability in Indonesia.
  Forests and forestry -- Economic aspects -- Indonesia; Human rights -- Indonesia; Environmental responsibility -- Indonesia; Watersheds -- Indonesia; Sustainable forestry -- Indonesia; Agroforestry -- Indonesia
- Reflection memo (Reports 017077), 2006 (Box 874, Reel R-9323)
  Reflection memo prepared by Ujjwal Pradhan evaluating natural resource management and activism in Indonesia.
  Forests and forestry -- Economic aspects -- Indonesia; Sustainable forestry -- Indonesia; Agroforestry -- Indonesia; Environmental responsibility -- Indonesia; Natural disasters -- Indonesia
- Reflection memo (Reports 017078), 2004 (Box 874, Reel R-9323)
  Reflection memo prepared by Betsy Theobald Richards evaluating the portfolio's interest in Native American arts and culture.
  Indian art -- North America; Indians of North America -- Material culture; Indigenous art; Indigenous peoples -- Politics and government; Art, Primitive -- North America; Indigenous peoples -- Civil rights -- North America
- Reflection memo (Reports 017079), 2005 (Box 874, Reel R-9323)
  Reflection memo prepared by Betsy Theobald Richards outlining the portfolio's interest in Native American arts and culture.
  Indian art -- North America; Indians of North America -- Material culture; Indigenous art -- North America; Indigenous peoples -- Politics and government; Art, Primitive -- North America; Indigenous peoples -- Civil rights -- North America
- Reflection memo (Reports 017080), 2004 (Box 874, Reel R-9323)
  Joint reflection memo prepared by Ganesan Balachander and Vasant Saberwal outlining the environmental development portfolio of the New Dehli office.
  Integrated agricultural systems -- India; Environmental justice -- India; Watershed management -- India; Agroforestry -- India; Green Revolution -- India
- Reflection memo (Reports 017081), 2004 (Box 875, Reel R-9323)
  Reflection memo prepared by Vasant Saberwal analyzing the New Dehli office portfolio's interest in integrated land and water management issues.
  Integrated agricultural systems -- India; Environmental justice -- India; Watershed management -- India; Environmental responsibility -- India; Rural renewal -- India
- Reflection memo (Reports 017082), 2006 (Box 875, Reel R-9323)
  Reflection memo prepared by Jael Silliman on the women's rights and gender equality issues of the PSJ New York portfolio.
  Women's rights; Feminism -- International cooperation; Feminism -- Philosophy; Feminism -- Moral and ethical aspects; Equality; Poor women -- Economic conditions
- Reflection memo 2005? (Reports 017083) (Box 875, Reel R-9323)
  Reflection memo prepared by Irina Yurna of the Moscow office analyzing the portfolio's interest in arts and culture.
  Contemporary art -- Russia (Federation); Humanities -- Russia (Federation); Arts -- Russia (Federation); Motion pictures -- Russia (Federation); Archives -- Collection management
- Reflection memo (Reports 017084), 2006 (Box 875, Reel R-9323)
  Reflection memo prepared by Alta Starr outlining the portfolio's interest in civil society, with emphasis placed on citizen participation in governance, public sphere access, and social justice organizations.
  Civil society -- United States; Civil rights -- United States; Democracy -- United States; Citizen's associations -- United States; Social justice -- United States; Bureaucracy -- United States
- Reflection memo (Reports 017085), 2005 (Box 875, Reel R-9323)
  Reflection memo prepared by Carla Sutherland of the Nairobi office, evaluating the education and sexuality portfolio with emphasis on women's education and gender equality.
  Health services for women -- East Africa; Reproductive health -- East Africa; HIV infections -- East Africa; Women's rights -- East Africa; Educational equalization -- East Africa; Women -- Education -- East Africa
- Reflection memo (Reports 017086), 2006 (Box 875, Reel R-9323)
  Reflection memo prepared by Carla Sutherland outlining portfolio's interest in educational opportunities for women and improving public discourse on gender, sexuality, and AIDS in Africa.
  Women's rights -- East Africa; HIV infections -- East Africa; Civil rights -- East Africa; Women -- Education -- East Africa; Sex instruction -- East Africa; Education -- Aims and objectives -- East Africa
- Reflection memo (Reports 017087), 2005 (Box 875, Reel R-9323)
  Reflection memo prepared by Aurelio Vianna evaluating the portfolio's interest in environmental sustainability for poor communities in the Amazon.
  Forests and forestry -- Brazil; Deforestation -- Brazil; Indigenous peoples -- Civil rights -- Brazil; Environmental responsibility -- Brazil
- Reflection memo (Reports 017088), 2006 (Box 875, Reel R-9323)
  Reflection memo prepared by Aurelio Vianna addressing the portfolio's interest in providing opportunity -- both social and economic -- to low-income communities of the Amazon.
  Deforestation -- Brazil; Indigenous peoples -- Civil rights -- Brazil; Environmental responsibility -- Brazil; Poor -- Brazil; Human rights -- Brazil
- Reflection memo (Reports 017089), 2004 (Box 875, Reel R-9323)
  Reflection memo prepared by Aurelio Vianna in his first year as program officer, outlining interest in indigenous communities in Brazil.
  Indigenous peoples -- Civil rights -- Brazil; Sustainable development -- Brazil; Deforestation -- Brazil; Indigenous peoples -- Ecology -- Brazil; Biodiversity -- Brazil; Environmental responsibility -- Brazil; Urban poor -- Brazil; Traditional ecological knowle
- Reflection memo (Reports 017090), 2005 (Box 875, Reel R-9323)
  Reflection memo prepared by Margaret Wilkerson outlining the portfolio's interest in media and arts funding, with emphasis placed on administrative issues confronted by the field.
  Endowments -- United States; Art and society -- United States; Artists -- United States; Art -- United States; Mass media and the arts -- United States
- Reflection memo (Reports 017091), 2006 (Box 875, Reel R-9323)
  Reflection memo prepared by Thomasina H. Williams evaluating the portfolio's interest in democracy and politics in America, with emphasis on diversity, leadership, and voting rights and participation.
  Civic leaders -- United States; Political participation -- United States; Politics, Practical -- United States; Voter registration -- United States; Voting rights -- United States; Democracy -- United States
- Reflection and close out memo confidential (Reports 017092), 2002 (Box 875, Reel R-9323)
  Reflection memo prepared by Christine Wing evaluating the portfolio's interest in peace and security funding, with emphasis on disarmament, conflict resolution, military cooperation and funding organizations.
  Disarmament; Nuclear weapons control; Military spending; Peace; Conflict resolution; World politics
- Reflection memo (Reports 017093), 2005 (Box 875, Reel R-9323)
  Reflection memo prepared by Susan Wood of the Vietnam and Thailand office, addressing human rights, sexuality and reproductive health issues, specifically HIV/AIDS awareness and growing gender-based violence concerns in Vietnam.
  Reproductive health -- Vietnam; Reproductive health -- Thailand; HIV/AIDS Infections -- Thailand; HIV/AIDS Infection -- Vietnam; Human sexuality -- Research; Sexually transmitted diseases; Violence; Sex role; Human rights; Youth and development
- Reflection memo (Reports 017094), 2003 (Box 875, Reel R-9323)
  Reflection memo prepared by Philip Yampolsky evaluating the Jakarta office's portfolio on arts and culture advancement in Indonesia, with emphasis placed on art education and access.
  Arts -- Indonesia; Art -- Study and teaching -- Indonesia; Documentary films -- Indonesia; Art -- Javanese; Art patronage -- Indonesia
- Reflection memo (Reports 017095), 2004 (Box 875, Reel R-9323)
  Reflection memo prepared by Philip Yampolsky of the Jakarta office outlining the portfolio's interest in local and traditional arts in Indonesia.
  Arts -- Indonesia; Arts -- Study and teaching -- Indonesia; Arts patronage -- Indonesia; Pluralism -- Indonesia; Documentary films -- Indonesia; Ethnomusicology; Booksellers and bookselling -- Indonesia
- Reflection memo (Reports 017096), 2005 (Box 875, Reel R-9323)
  Reflection memo prepared by Philip Yampolsky evaluating the status of arts and culture work in Indonesia.
  Arts -- Indonesia; Arts -- Study and teaching -- Indonesia; Arts patronage -- Indonesia; Ethnomusicology; Folk music -- Indonesia; Documentary films
- Ford Foundation, 70 years: Delivering on a promise to advance human welfare (Reports 017097), 2007 (Box 875, Reel R-9323)
  Celebrating 70 years of the Foundation's contributions to improving lives, this booklet contains a comprehensive pull-out timeline marking key moments in Ford history. Essays from board Chair Kathryn Fuller and President Susan Berresford highlight the Fou
  Delivering on a promise to advance human welfare
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations; Human rights; Social justice; Civil rights
- Reproductive rights grantmaking review (Reports 017098), 2002 (Box 875, Reel R-9323)
  Memo prepared by Jerry Maldonado providing extensive summaries of all Foundation activities and achievements in the field of reproductive rights, covering the years 1994 to 2002, with individual office reports and grantee summaries.
  Reproductive health; Human rights; Women's rights; Sex instruction; HIV infections; Gender discrimination; Gender-based violence; Health care reform; Human sexuality; Birth control; Abortion; Human reproduction -- Law and legislation; AIDS (Disease) -- Prevention
- Challenges and opportunities in rural America: Looking at the data and listening to the practitioners a report to the Ford Foundation's asset and community development program March 1 (Reports 017099), 2006 (Box 875, Reel R-9323)
  Rural poverty -- United States; Environmental responsibility -- United States; Civil rights -- United States; Globalization -- United States; Unemployment -- United States; Community development -- Economic aspects -- United States; Rural-urban migration
- The forestry and society network: Securing a sustainable future (Reports 017100), 2005 (Box 875, Reel R-9323)
  Report evaluates the need for Foundation support in the area of publication for forestry research, focusing on support for the Forestry and Society Network of the Institute of Forestry Science and Technology Information at the Chinese Academy of Forestry.
  Forests and forestry -- China; Sustainable forestry -- China; Forest conservation -- China; Forestry -- Periodicals; Social forestry programs
- Notes for the hand-over of Barbara's current US initiative (Strengthening the legitimacy and policy relevance of sexuality research in the U.S.) to new U.S. SRH PO Dorinda Welle 2005 (Reports 017101), 2006 (Box 875, Reel R-9323)
  Human sexuality -- Research -- United States; Reproductive health -- United States; Sexology -- United States; Public policy -- United States; Sexual behavior -- United States; Sexually transmitted diseases -- United States; Women's rights -- United States
- Women in development report (Reports 017102), 2005 (Box 875, Reel R-9323)
  Report outlines the capacity-building grants in the women in development portfolio, with summary of grantees and achievements in the field.
  Women's rights; Feminism -- Moral and ethical aspects; Women's studies; Women in politics; Gender identity; Sexual minorities; Women in development
- The working capital fund: A comprehensive capacity building program for mid-sized culturally-specific arts organizations final evaluation of round twodraft (Reports 017103), 2003 (Box 875, Reel R-9323)
  10001070
  Harder & Company Community Research
  FOR EVALUATION AND DOCUMENTATION OF THE FIRST AND SECOND ROUNDS OF THE WORKING CAPITAL FUND, A NATIONAL DEMONSTRATION PROJECT INITIATED BY THE FOUNDATION TO STRENGTHEN MINORITY ARTS ORGANIZATIONS
  Working capital; Arts patronage -- United States; Art and society -- United States; Art -- United States; Artists -- United States; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Finance -- Statistics; Theater -- United States
- A foundation goes to school: The Ford Foundation comprehensive school improvement program 1960 (Reports 017104), 1972
  The Ford Foundation began making grants in Vietnam in the early 1990's and was issued a license to establish an office in Hanoi in October 1996. During its first decade, the Foundation approved more than 550 grants to organizations and individuals in Viet
  Public Policy and Social Organization
  Education -- Vietnam; Educational change -- Vietnam; Education -- Statistics -- Vietnam
- Measuring investment results by the unit method (Reports 017105), 1975
  The Ford Foundation makes grants in Development Finance; Education and Scholarship; E&D; International Cooperation; Media, Arts and Culture; and Sexuality and Reproductive Health.
  Finance/Office of the Vice President
  The Educational Endowment Series;[Ford Foundation publications]
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States; Investments; Dividends -- Accounting
- International organizations and law: A program paper of the Ford Foundation (Reports 017106), 1990
  A Ford Foundation Program Paper reviewing the Foundation's longstanding interest in strengthening international organizations and law and outlining areas of future grant making.
  International agencies -- Research; International coOperation -- Research; International law -- Research
- Hispanic theater in the United States and Puerto Rico: A report to the Ford Foundation (Reports 017107), 1988
  A survey of contemporary Hispanic theater and its historical context.
  United States and International Affairs Program/Education and Culture
  Hispanic American theater -- United States; Hispanic American theater -- Puerto Rico; Theater -- Political aspects -- United States; Theater -- Political aspects -- Puerto Rico
- Violence against women: Addressing a global problem Ford Foundation Women's Program Forum (Reports 017108), 1992
  A seminar on violence against women and programs to combat it. Includes discussion of services for battered women and reforms in the criminal justice system. A publication of the Women's Program Forum.
  Ford Foundation. Women's Program Forum
  Women -- Crimes against -- Congresses; Women's rights -- Worldwide; Feminism -- Worldwide; Women's status -- Worldwide; Domestic violence -- Worldwide
- Women in the world: A Ford Foundation position paper (Reports 017109), 1980
  In 1980 Ford more than doubled its funding of programs aimed at advancing women's roles and opportunities around the world, investing a total of $19.3 million. This position paper outlines in general terms the effects of gender discrimination on women aro
  Education and Public Policy (EPP)/Public Policy and Social Organization
  Women's rights; Sex discrimination against women; Discrimination in employment; Women -- Economic conditions
- Women in the arts: Current debates, future directions a dialogue with four distinguished performing artists and scholars (Reports 017110), 1989
  Discussion among four distinguished artists and scholars: Martha Boesing, Laura Dean, Zelda Fichlander and Margaret B. Wilkerson. A publication of the Women's Program Forum.
  Women artists; Women in art; Women's rights; Feminism; Women dancers -- United States
- Hispanics: Challenges and opportunities: A working paper for the Ford Foundation (Reports 017111), 1984
  A Ford Foundation Working Paper that discusses the demographic, economic, social and political situation of Hispanics in the United States today. Also describes the Foundation's initiatives to address the needs of this growing population.
  A look at the demographic, economic, social and political situation in the U.S. today, and at the Ford Foundation's initiatives to address the needs and impact of this growing population.
  Hispanic Americans -- Services for -- United States; Hispanic Americans -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Hispanic Americans -- Social conditions; Hispanic Americans -- Economic conditions; Discrimination -- United States; Puerto Rico -- Economic conditions
- Recovering our confidence: New York and the civic spirit (Reports 017112), 1991
  A speech delivered at the Alumni Association of the City College of New York, Nov. 1, 1990. Mr. Thomas was awarded the college's John H. Finley Medal.
  Civil rights -- New York; Human rights -- New York; Citizenship -- United States; Political participation -- United States
- Women, children, and poverty in America: A working paper from the Ford Foundation (Reports 017113), 1985
  A Ford Foundation Working Paper that reviews the problems facing low-income families headed by women, and describes some current and planned Foundation responses.
  A look at the problems facing low-income families headed by women and at some current and planned Ford Foundation responses
  Women's rights -- United States; Poor women -- United States; Economic assistance, Domestic -- United States; Teenage pregnancy -- United States; Birth control -- United States
- The law and the lore of endowment funds: A report to the Ford Foundation (Reports 017114), 1969
  Growing costs of higher education outpaced increases in endowments throughout the 1960's. This report examines the laws governing the endowment funds of colleges and universities with the goal of strengthening efforts to improve endowment income. While th
  Administration/Program Related Investments
  Endowments -- United States; Investments -- Law and legislation -- United States; Corporations -- Finance -- United States; Corporations -- Charitable contributions -- Law and legislation
- Managing educational endowments: A report to the Ford Foundation (Reports 017115), 1969
  The Educational Endowment Series
  Endowments -- United States; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States; Investments -- Law and legislation -- United States; Education -- Finance -- United States
- Race relations and ethnicity (Reports 017116), 1985
  Speech delivered at the first Whitney M. Young, Jr. Memorial Lecture at Columbia University, Oct. 24, 1984, which discusses race, ethnic relations, and affirmative action internationally, with special emphasis on South Africa and the United States.
  Discrimination -- United States; Racism -- United States; Pluralism -- United States; African Americans -- Social conditions -- United States
- New approaches to conflict resolution: A Ford Foundation report (Reports 017117), 1978
  A discussion of efforts to strengthen the capacity of existing institutions in the field of conflict resolution, of new ways, such as mediation, of handling disputes outside formal legal systems, and of proposed systematic reforms that tend to avert or si
  Dispute resolution (Law); Conflict management; Peacemaking; Dispute settlement; Peace -- Societies, etc.; Conciliation (Civil procedure); Social problems
- Ford Foundation's work in population: A working paper for the Ford Foundation (Reports 017118), 1985
  This working paper is a result of a review of the Ford Foundation's work to slow population growth against the background of a reduction in U.S. government support for population-related activities in the early 1980's. The report outlines key demographic
  A review of past and present emphases and a discussion of plans to expand the Foundation's population programs based on current work.
  Birth control; Population density; Contraception; Family policy -- Developing countries; Urbanization -- Social conditions
- Fulfilling America's promise (Reports 017119), 1991
  A speech delivered at the Chicago Council on Urban Affairs, April 23, 1991. A discussion of programs that are meeting the challenges of renewing American communities and rebuilding lives burdened by poverty.
  Globalization; International cooperation; Urbanization -- Social aspects; Community development; Economic stabilization -- United States; Intergovernmental fiscal relations -- United States; Urban poor -- United States
- Forestry for Sustainable Rural Development: A Review of Ford Foundation-Supported Community Forestry Programs in Asia (Reports 017120), 1998
  Describes how woodland communities in Asia are using community forestry to raise incomes and protect the environment.
  Forestry projects -- Asia; Social forestry programs -- Asia; Rural development projects -- Asia; Forests and foresty -- Economic aspects -- Asia; Sustainable forestry -- Asia
- Women's studies in the United States: A report to the Ford Foundation (Reports 017121), 1986
  A report on the development and future of women's studies at the university level.
  Women's studies -- United States; Women -- Study and teaching -- United States; Feminism -- United States; Women -- History -- United States
- The Ford Foundation and the United Nations (Reports 017122), 1996
  A report, written by Shepard Forman, that reviews the Foundation's support for the work of the United Nations, its programs, and related activities since 1951. Includes a foreword by Brian Urquhart.
  Human rights; Rule of law; Sustainable development -- Law and legislation; Community development -- Social aspects
- Innovations in state and local government 1986 an awards program of the Ford Foundation in collaboration with the John F. Kennedy School of Government at Harvard University (Reports 017123)
  Community development -- United States; Social service -- United States; Adoption -- United States; Urban poor -- United States; Environmental responsibility -- United States; People with disabilities -- United States; Nursing -- United States; Older people
- Innovations in state and local government 1987 an awards program of the Ford Foundation in collaboration with the John F. Kennedy School of Government at Harvard University (Reports 017124)
  Imprisonment -- United States; Wetland conservation -- United States; Family violence -- United States; Birth control -- United States; Water--Pollution -- United States; Sewage -- United States; After-school programs -- United States; Employment -- United States
- Innovations in state and local government 1988 an awards program of the Ford Foundation in collaboration with the John F. Kennedy School of Government at Harvard University (Reports 017125)
  Homelessness -- United States; Land use -- Planning -- United States; Urban poverty -- United States; Court records -- United States; Education -- United States; Vocational training -- United States; Criminal Justice, Administration of -- United States; Racism
- Innovations in state and local government 1990 an awards program of the Ford Foundation in collaboration with the John F. Kennedy School of Government at Harvard University (Reports 017126)